you are told some fable about
вам рассказывают какую-то басню про
Novgorod what does the word Novgorod mean
Новгород что означает слово Новгород
well it is clear there is a New City everything is a New
ну понятно там Новый город все Новый
City if there is a new city then there were Well
город если есть новый город значит были
naturally there were yes old cities
Ну естественно были да старые города
hello greetings I am from the city of
здравствуйте приветствую я из города
Khmelnitsky where are you from the city of Samara
Хмельницкий вы откуда город Самара
Russia understood what you are talking about oh I don't
Россия понял о чём общаетесь ой пока не
know yet nothing just came in listen
знаю пока ни о чём просто зашёл слушайте
I remember I am a little older than you I
я помню я немножко постарше вас я
remember Samara was called something like Kuibyshev it was a
помню Самара называлась вроде Куйбышев
matter it was a matter and why was it
было дело было дело а почему его
renamed what kind of decommunization did
переименовали что за декоммунизация у
you have that you took Soviet names
вас пошла что вы советские названия
and renamed them well how is
взяли и переименовали
decommunization like that well why did
ну как декоммунизация вот так вот ну а
you check decommunization
зачем вы проверили декоммунизацию
why well how are historical names and as
зачем ну как исторические названия и как
if it was no longer relevant Kubishevo
бы уже было не актуально кубишев
probably
наверное
well for example Kaliningrad was not
ну например Калининград не
renamed to its historical name
переименовали в историческое название
Knicksberg
Книксберг
well Kaliningrad was like German
ну Калининград же типа был немецкий
now hurray
теперь ура
ours therefore so and Samara also was was
наш поэтому так и и Самара также
Turkic became hurray yours
был был тюркский стал ура ваш
no Samara was built from scratch as a
нет Самара была с нуля построена как
fortress stop stop stop what does the
крепость стоп стоп стоп что означает
word Samara mean Samara well
слово Самара
I understood yes it is  some
самара ну я понял да это какое-то
Tatar name most likely because well yes
татарское скорее всего название потому
Turkic these are
что ну это да тюрские это там всюда жили
Turkic peoples who lived everywhere these are conquered
тюркские народы это завоёванные
territories just like with Kaliningrad well
территории так же как с Калининградом
yes we have and everywhere from scratch a fortress
ну да мы име и всюду с нуля крепость
also for example with Odessa yes
также например с Одессой да
Russians say myth yes what Katerina
россияне говорят миф да что там Катерина
built Odessa or so then there was the
построила Одессу или так дальше там был
city of Khadzhibey they renamed it
город Хаджибей переименовали его в
Odessa and then it continued to develop
Одессу и дальше он дальше развиваться
for example so and here it turns out well look
например так и тут получается ну смотри
come on so can you name me at least
давай так вот можешь мне назвать хоть
one city on the territory of the Russian
один город на территории Российской
Federation
Федерации
uh let's say from the Volga region to the Far
ээ скажем от Поволжья и до Дальнего
East yes which was built by a non-Russian I
Востока да который построили не русский
mean what's the question which built
в смысле в чём вопрос который построил
look well look Samara who what people
смотри ну смотри Самара кто какой народ
built the city of Samara
построил город Самара
well I have no idea what people either
ну я без понятия какой народ либо
local or newcomers there are two options
местный либо пришедший тут два варианта
well newcomers - who were there
ну пришедшие - это кто там были
newcomers
пришедшие
well newcomers meaning when the
ну пришедшие имеется в виду когда
Russian Empire was building the kstan so here the
Российской империи строилась кстана вот
question can you name me at least
так вот вопрос можешь мне назвать хоть
one city yes from the Volga region to the Far
один город да от Поволжья и до Дальнего
East which was built by
Востока который был построен
locals of the empire that didn't come well
местными непришедшей империи
right  as a city I don't know well in
ну прямо как город я не знаю ну
any case there were some settlements not that's it yes the
по-любому же были какие-то поселения не
question is interesting yes why does it
вот вот да вопрос интересный да почему
turn out that in modern
так получается что в современная история
Russian history it shows that all the cities
России показывает так что все города
seem to have become some kind of Russian
вроде как ээ делались какими-то русскими
and before that there were no cities or states well
а до этого там ни городов ни государств
if we talk about some Yakutia then as
ну если говорить про какую-то Якутию то
such states maybe there really weren't any like there
как таковых государств может и правда не
weren't let's
как не было
say I mean directly the northern
скажем я имею в виду прямо северное
northern there
северное там
what is the north north we are not
что северно север мы сейчас не про
talking about the northern northern now we
северное северные говорим вот мы сейчас
are talking about Samara and all these
говорим про Самару и все вот эти
populated areas like Russia
населённые территории типа России
well this is real look come on so uh you
ну это реально смотри давай так ээ ты
know the oldest city in Russia the most
знаешь самый старый город России самый
ancient city in Russia m
древний город России м
so well Rus' said here the
так ну Руси сказа вот современной
most ancient city of the modern Russian Federation
Российской Федерации самый старинный
m well decided to assume that Novgorod
м ну решино предположить что Новгород
doesn't exist what Novgorod
нет какой Новгород
Derbent you know where Derbent is
дербент знаешь где Дербент находится
well approximately to be honest not very not
ну примерно если честно не очень не
very better look at the map in Dagestan in
очень лучше посмотреть на карту в Даге в
Dagestan look just for the sake of interest
Дагестане посмотри вот ради интереса вот
go to Wikipedia look at the history of
зайди в Википедию посмотри историю
Derbent how many thousands of years ago it  was
Дербента сколько тысяч лет назад он был
already a city
уже городом
Derbent so wow and really in 438
дербент так ух ты и правда в 438 году
AD yes at least
нашей эры да как минимум
2,000 there are more even skov up to 5,000
2.000 там больше даже сков до 5.000
I think but 2,000 are definitely confirmed
считаю но 2.000 точно подтверждённы
so look it turns out yes
есть так вот смотри получается да
uh you are told some fable about
ээ вам рассказывают какую-то басню про
Novgorod what does the word Novgorod mean well it is
Новгород что означает слово Новгород
clear there is a New City everything is a new
ну понятно там Новый город все новый
city if there is a new city then there were well
город если есть новый город значит были
naturally there were old cities the
ну естественно были да старые города
question: what are these old cities that
вопрос: что же это за старые города что
they are not there but there is only Novgorod the very
их нету а вот есть только Новгород самый
first well what is the
первый
question that I just
ну в чём вопрос в том что я просто
said Novgorod no no
сказал Новгород
this is very interesting because
нет нет это очень интересно потому что
look Novgorod yes modern
смотри Новгород да современная
Russian fake this
российская фейковая вот эта
historiography it begins here
историография она начинает вот
political policy yes it wants to
политическая политика да она хочет
attribute that Novgorod was the first
приписать что Новгород был первым
city from it there went on other
городом из него там пошли дальше другие
cities and so on Rus' went yes but for
города и так дальше Русь пошла да но
example in the 7th century yes no
никакой например в VII веке да никаких
archaeological excavations in Slavyansk
археологических раскопок славянске
there are none in Novgorod yes that is
никаких в Новгороде нету да то есть
Novgorod did not exist in the 6th century yes in
Новгорода не было ни в VI веке да по
fact in short not in the ninth only  here That
сути короче ни в девятом только вот То
is Novgorod and by the name it could not have been
есть Новгород и по названию он не мог
earlier than other cities
быть раньше других городов
oh question no well it's just I called the
о вопрос нет ну это просто я назвал
New city Miroslav like Samara question
Новый городо Мирослав как Самар вопрос
yes question uh for example the city of
да вопрос ээ например город
Saratov so
Саратов так
let's say you know if you are from Samara
допустим знаешь вот если ты из Самары
Saratov is not that far away yes yes
Саратов же вроде не совсем далеко да да
yes
да
uh when the settlement appeared there the
ээ когда там появилось поселение
city I don't know who founded it I don't know I haven't
город не знаю кто основал его
been there actually on
не знаю я там не был собственно ни на
any excursions no I don't know that's also they
каких экскурсиях не не знаю вот тоже
say a fortress Russians yes and there was also an
говорят крепость россияне да а там ещё
ancient Golden Horde city now
древний золотоордынский город был сейчас
it's part uh
это часть ээ
Saratov Uvik I think it was called now
Саратова увик по-моему назывался сейчас
I'll check to be sure Uvik
я проверю чтобы точно Увик
well on Google Ukik ukek he yes he Ukik and
ну на Google Укик укек он да он Укик и
Uvik is written yes here is the microdistrict Uvik
Увик пишется да вот микрорайон Увик
in Saratov yes and the city was called ancient
в Саратове да а город назывался древний
Ukik
Укик
look Ukik yes it writes: "One of the
вот посмотри Укик да пишет: "Один из
largest cities of the Golden Horde having the
крупнейших городов Золотой РДы имеющий
status of a federal object of cultural
статус федерального объекта культурного
heritage of Russia" the appearance of the city
наследия России" появление города
dates back to the 10th century and so on tammerla the
относится к X веке и так дальше таммерла
modern microdistrict Saratov
современный микрорайон Саратов
located on the territory of the ancient
находящийся на территории древнего
city has a similar name
города носит схожее название
Uek that is Saratov yes how  Russian
Уек то есть Саратов да как российская
historiography here Novgorod appeared
историография вот тут появился Новгород
here they made Saratov yes, nothing-nothing
тут сделали Саратов да ничего-ничего
naked tribes ran and then some
бегали голые племена а тут какой-то
Saratov appeared yes and
Саратов появился да
what's more with an incomprehensible name what does the
вот причём с непонятным названием что
word Saratov mean
означает слово Саратов
well people most likely not a Russian
ну людей скорее всего не российское
name yes but from the Turkic names
название вот да а с тюркских названий
Sarytau Yellow
Сарытау Жёлтая
Mountain everything and everything is clear true for
гора всё и всё чётко правда
example if in Russian or in
вот например если в русском языке или в
Ukrainian
украинском
Belogorye is clear White Mountain is true that's
Белогорье понятно Белая гора правда вот
those and Saratov Yellow Mountain it just
вот те и Саратов Жёлтая гора вот просто
turns out how when the Russian
получается как что когда Российская
Empire captured these territories then it was
империя захватывала эти территории потом
necessary to rewrite history that as if
нужно было переписать историю что как бы
here initially some wild
тут вот изначально бегали какие-то дикие
incomprehensible people ran yes without a state without
непонятные люди да без государства без
cities and then they came and brought
городов а тут вот им пришли и принесли
almost civilization well yes well
чуть ли не цивилизацию
again it depends on the place I mean of
да ну опять же зависит от места я имею в
course yes in the Volga region I agree there
виду конечно да в Поволчие соглашусь там
and in the Urals too and
и на Урале тоже а
somewhere in Far Siberia Yakutia there well
где-нибудь Дальняя Сибирь Якутия там ну
there and it's true Chukchi tribes and all that
там же и правда чукчи племена и все дела
stop stop stop let's do it in Yakutia not
стоп стоп стоп давай так в Якутии не
Chukchi in Yakutia  Sakha, uh, Sakha are
чукчи в Якутии саха вот ээ саха - это
Turks, they are the same as Kazakhs, the same as
тюрки они так же как казахи так же как
other Turks, Sakha are a Turkic people,
другие тюрки саха - это тюркский народ
yes, well, their way of life itself is probably
ну да ну у них сам образ жизни наверное
nomadic, it does not imply koro, no, look,
кочевой он не подразумевает коро нет
Chukchi and Chukchi are Chukotka, the question is
смотри чук и чукча - это чукотка вопрос
nomadic, look, come on, you say it, uh, a nomadic way of
кочевой смотри давай так ты говоришь ээ
life does not imply
образ жизни кочевой не подразумевает
cities, the Golden Horde consisted of nomadic
города золотая орда состояла из кочевых
peoples,
народов
yes, I understand everything, yes, I agree, we
ну да всё я понял да соглаша мы мы
looked at Saratov, there,
смотрели Саратов там
Sary, Sarai, Batu, and so on, there were cities,
Сары Сарай Бату и так дальше города были
that is, uh, and if we look, for example, the
то есть ээ и если мы посмотрим например
Kazakhs are a nomadic people,
вот казахи это кочевой народ
yes, or half-nomadic, which means nomadic,
ну да или получевой что означает кочевой
they did not have any territory, they
они не имели никакой территории где-то
wandered somewhere, or they wandered because
бродили или они кочевали потому что у
they had z, where they lived for the winter, and in the summer
них были з э где они на зиму жили а лето
they grazed pastures, for example, uh, this is
они пастбище выпасали например ээ это
thinness, somehow in Russian, livestock, well,
худобу както порусски живность
naturally, the second option, yes, yes, that is,
ну естественно да второй вариант да да
uh, there was no such thing, yes, what
вот то есть ээ не было такого да что
if millions of people lived on this territory,
если на этой территории проживали
they had an organization in any case
миллионы людей у них по-любому была
political social and
организация политическая социальная и
so on it can't be but just that the
так дальше не может быть да только что
Golden Horde was and there were cities and that
вот Золотая Орда была и города были да и
was all and then hop in short and there were no cities
всё было а тут гоп короче и ни городов
like no
не стало типа ни
states they broke up into for example
государств они распались на вот например
if you take uh the Siberian
если возьмёшь ээ Сибирское
Khanate you know there was such a state well
ханство знаешь такое было государство
specifically about the Siberian no
ну конкретно про сибирское нет вот
now I'm now looking at two like
сейчас я сейчас смотрю на два как
it or I wasn't mistaken yes the Siberian Khanate
она или я не ошибся да сибирское ханство
yes so the Tatar feudal
вот да так татарское феодальное
state in Western Siberia
государство в Западной Сибири
formed at the end of the 15th century as a
образовавшееся в конце XV века в
result of the collapse of the Golden Horde
результате распада Золотой Орды
bordered on the Perm land Nagai
граничила с Пермской землёй Нагайской
Horde Kazakh Khanate and
Ордой Казахским ханством и
Tilyut so it existed now I will say it
Тилютом вот существовала сейчас скажу
existed from 1465 to 1588 the capital of
существовала с 1465 по 1588 год столица
Chengitura Kashlyk there were
Ченгитура Кашлык вот были
cities and so on it's
города и так дальше
interesting interesting it turns out and it
интересно интересно получается и
turns out itself if we look yes
получается вот сама если мы смотрим да
what are all the names of the rivers there and so on
что все названия там рек да и так дальше
in these territories there is a city they are
вот в этих территориях там город они
Turkic because Turkic peoples
тюркские потому что там тюркские народы
lived there yes for quite a long time it was theirs
жили да довольно долго это была ихняя
as if and more if we look  what
как бы и больше того если мы посмотрим
is the Russian Empire
то что такое Российская империя
who were part of who were the nobles in the
кто входили кто были дворянами в
Russian Empire basically
Российской империи в основном
who were well
кто были ну
Russians what Russians well tell me the
русские каких русских а ну назови мне
Russian nobles
русских дворян
okay okay I don't know I'm simple okay
давай хорошо давай не знаю я простой
let's try for example the family uh the
хорошо давай попробуем например род ээ
noble family Yusupov what does Yusupov mean I do
дворянский род Юсуповы что означает
n't know what it means well yes it sounds like not
не знаю что означает ну да звучит как не
Russian yes Yusup Yusuf is a Turkic
русский да юсуп юсуф - это имя тюркское
name similar to Joseph yes Yusuf that is they were uh
имя аналог Иосиф да юсуф то есть они
these then uh what does Kutuzov mean well I
были ээ эти потом ээ что означает
also don't know Kutuz is a Turkic word yes
ну тоже не знаю кутуз тюрское слово да
so on what does
так дальше что означает
Lermontov mean is it from the Scottish family
лермонтов это от шотландского рода
Lermont
Лермонт
what does
что означает
[music]
[музыка]
Bogration mean I also don't know yes these were
богратион вот тоже не знаю да это
Georgian princes yes who were noble
грузинские князья были да которые знатью
in the Roman Empire that is and if we
в Римской империи то есть и если мы
look uh in the Russian Empire yes there were a
смотрим ээ в Российской империи да очень
lot of noble families they were
много знатных родов это были
Turks now I'm really interested I'll
тюрки вот я сейчас прямо интересно я
read now like this now it's
сейчас прочитаю вот так сейчас
interesting so I
интересно
also remembered Turgenev you know
так также вот вспомнил Тургенев знаешь
such a writer yes of course what does Turgenev mean well
писателя такого да конечно что означает
I don't know what it means in Turgen -
ну я не знаю что это значит во Турген -
this is also a Turkic now now
это тоже тюрская сейчас сейчас
now this is also a Turkic family was yes
сейчас это тоже тюркский род был да
here Ivan Sergeevich Turgenev came
вот Иван Сергеевич Тургенев происходил
from an old noble family the
из старинного дворянского рода
founder of which was the Tatar
родоначальником которого был татарский
Murza Lev Turgen who left the Horde to the
Мурза Лев Турген выехавший из Орды к
Grand Duke Vasily and yes dark in
великому князю Василию и да тёмному в
144 baptized under the name Ivan that
144 е хрестившийся под именем Иван то
is if we
есть если мы
look at the majority
посмотрим ээ большинство
of the Moscow principality of all sorts of
из Московского княжества всяких там
boyar and so on families yes they were
боярских и так дальше родов да они были
Tatars and other
татарами и другими
Turks how can you explain this can you
тюрками как так объяснить можешь мне
explain to me why so why so where
объяснить почему так
in the Russian it seems like a
откуда в русском вроде как бы
principality with uh noble families almost all
княжестве с ээ дворянские роды почти все
some kind of Turkic
какие-то тюркские
well as in Russian
ну как в русском
well Moscow if you think that it
ну московское если вы считаете что это
was Russian well no not
было русское
quite how to say not quite
ну нет не совсем как сказать не совсем
let's well
давай
naturally in Russia yes a lot in the
ну естественно в России да много в
sewer let's say so
сточных скажем так
roots and I
корней и у меня
also have from my grandmother's side well so what well yes
тоже с со стороны
nothing surprising yes no
так что ну да ничего удивительного да
so look let's look again let's
нет так смотри вот давай посмотрим ещё
think if it was a Slavic
раз подумаем если это было славянское
state Moscow principality  yes how did it
государство московское княжество да как
happen that all the nobility were
так получилось что вся знать была
some kind of Turkic
каких-то там тюркских
clans then German clans yes
родов потом уже немецких ещё родов да
like well, not Russian well, there
типа ну вот не русских
was the Horde and all that, well, the Horde the Horde was gone yes the
ну была же Орда все дела так ну орда
Horde was gone why
Орды не стало да орды не стало почему
after the Horde it seems like the Moscow Tsar
после Орды вроде как ээ московский царь
granted these noble titles
да жаловал вот эти дворянские титулы
exactly somehow to the Turkic cities
именно как-то вот тюркским городам
why did it happen well
почему так получилось
because they were local they needed
ну потому что они местные там нужен был
some kind of their own local so why not
какой-то свой местный так а почему не
where is the local well in Moscow yes why are
где местный ну вот в Москве да почему
all the locals in Moscow some kind of
все местные в Москве получаются какие-то
Tatars and so on
там татары и так дальше
no I mean local not in Moscow but
нет я имею в виду местным не в Москве а
in some cities already well and in
там в каких-нибудь городах уже ну а в
Moscow well where are the Slavic these clans well no
Москве ну а где же славянские вот эти
now why not and how is this
ну нету ну сейчас а почему нету и как
state like Russian and all
это государство вроде русских а все роды
these noble clans are not
эти дворянские не
Russian
русские
interesting question didn't
интересный вопрос не
think about it now I'll find so the
задумывался сейчас я найду
Yusupovs too yes they are from the Tatars
так вот Юсуповы тоже да это от татарских
yes they served the
да отслужило
Tatars now I'm interested so the
татар сейчас мне интересно так
most famous clans of Tatar
вот самые известные роды татарского
origin
происхождения
so it's interesting we
так вот интересно
take it from the Urusovs I  I think we won't even
берём так от Урусовы я думаю тут даже не
argue here that this is Tatar so
будем спорить что это да татарский так
Bayushevs
Баюшевы
Bayushevs also so from Tatar Murs came the
баюшевы тоже так от татарских мурс пошёл
distant ancestor of the princes Bayushev Bayush
далёкий предок князей Баюшевы Баюш
Razgildeev so
Разгильдеев так
on so to speak now now
дальше так сказать сейчас сейчас
now it is not
сейчас не
in order
упорядочено
Kozurovs also well now
козуровы тоже
name me some kind of
ну вот назови мне какой-то вот какие ты
noble families name me at least
помнишь дворянские роды назови мне хоть
someone you remember so that Russians
кого-то кого ты помнишь чтобы русские
were I'm interested
были мне интересно
so that
чтоб
[music]
[музыка]
Russians yes Vydova seems not to sound Russian
русские да выдова вроде не по-русски
yes probably well I can't
да наверно
remember yes I can't well for the
ну вот не могу вспомнить да не могу ну
sake of interest let's google it long mouth because
ради интереса загуглим довго рот потому
these can be church
что это же могут быть там церковные
so and
так
so Akhitinsky
о так Ахитинского
now here Davydovs princely count and
сейчас вот Давыдовы княжеский графские и
noble families numbering 76 descendants of
дворянские рода числом 76 потомство
Murza Minchak not Russian by
Мурзы Минчака не русские по
origin having left the great Horde
происхождению выехавшего из большой орды
you teach everything right now I
преподаете всё вот прямо открыл мне аж
was really interested Dadova
интересно было Дадова
yes everything is Tatar
да всё татарский
Murzaminchak and and there is also  several
мурзаминчак а и ещё вот есть несколько
families there are also princes Davydov descendants of the
родов есть ещё князья Давыдовы потомки
Georgian Tsar Alexander
грузинского царя Александра
I those Davydovs are also not
I те Давыдовы тоже не
Russian uh descendants the next family
русские э потомство следующий род
Davydov descendants of Murza Minchak this one who
Давыдовы потомство Мурзы Минчака вот
left the great horde the third
этого выехавший из большой орды третий
uh branch also Davydov separate descendants of
ээ ветка тоже Давыдова отдельный потомки
Davyd Be who owned a tsimak of Armenian
Давыда Бе владевшего цимаком армянского
origin then he says: "So and so
происхождения потом говорит: "Так и так
on"
дальше"
in short let's try for the sake of interest to
короче давай попробуем вот ради интереса
find some Russian family
найти какой-то русский род
well then I'll also use so to speak I'm
ну тогда тоже воспользу так сказать мне
interested yes
мне интересно да
because if we take Pushkin Pushkin is
потому что если возьмём Пушкин Пушкин
also not Russian well yes here is
тоже не русский да ну да
Dostoevsky by the way here is Dostoevsky
вот Достоевский кстати вот Достоевский
also not
тоже не
Russian this is a family which in my opinion is a
русский это ээ род который по-моему
Tatar family which in Belarus had uh
татарский род который в Беларуси имел ээ
in the village in the village of Dostoeva
в селе в деревне Достоева
land and that's why they called themselves
землю и поэтому они назвались
Dostoevsky now I'll check well
Достоевский сейчас я проверю а ну
or if I'm not
или если я не
mistaken vertishcheto
ошибаюсь вертището
[music]
[музыка]
well yes look Dostoevsky for the sake of interest
вот да смотри Достоевский ради интереса
you can open Wikipedia
ты же можешь открыть Википедию
Dostoevsky family write and so that not  it was
достоевский род напиши и чтоб не было
that I was deceiving so the noble family
что я обманываю так дворянский род
being the branches of the Rodashchevs means the
являющийся ветвей родащевы значит род
Dostoevsky family originates from the boyar
Достоевский берёт своё начало от боярина
Danil Ivanovich
Данила Ивановича
Irtyshchev that is also already you see not the
Иртищева то есть тоже уже видишь не
Russian name just like there is Irtysh but
русское название так же как есть Иртыш а
this is Irtysh and so
это Иртищ
on so so so the ancestor of Danil
вот и дальше тактактак предком Данила
Ivanovich Irtyshche according to the researcher
Ивановича Иртище по мнению исследователя
is was mentioned in
является являлся упоминаемым в
historical sources Tatar
исторических истории источниках татарин
Aslan Chelebimu Murza who in 1389
Аслан Челебиму Мурза который в 1389 году
left the Golden Horde and was baptized in
покинул Золотую Орду и был крещён в
Orthodoxy by the Moscow prince Dmitry
православии московским князем Дмитрием
Donskoy so the son of this Tatar was nicknamed
Донски вот сына этого татарина прозвали
wide mouth and his descendants mouth became
широким ртом а его потомки рта стали
rtishchev so from the mouth of the
ртищевым вот так от рта
Gertishchevs on which were depicted a
гербтищевых на котором были изображены
half-moon hexagonal star and a pair of
полумеса шестиугольная звезда и пара
armed Tatars confirms the
вооружённых татар подтверждает
non-Orthodox origin of the family well
неправославное происхождение рода
here I found the Belkins and Barsukovs Belkin
ну вот нашёл Белкины и Барсуковы белкины
and Barsukovs two maybe yes no I did not
и Барсуковы две может быть да не не
hear the wiring but for the sake of interest
слышал проводки но ради интереса
I will look Barsukovs well it
посмотрю барсуковы
says there that it is there now and
ну там написано что это там сейчас и
Beltina yes  yes, I'll turn off the alarm sound in a minute, you
Белтина да да сейчас минуту выключу звук
see, your country is attacking us, it
тревоги видишь ваша страна атакует нас
wants to kill more people, so the Belkins or Belkin's Belkins,
хочет убить ещё людей так Белкины или
well, Belkins, and Belkins and Barsukovs, that's
белкины ну Белки а Белкины и Барсуковы
cool, that's
прикольно
interesting now, yes, I've never heard of
та сейчас интересно да не слышал даже
such a thing, the
такие
Barsukovs, so from Stepan Semenovich,
та Барсуковы так от Степана Семёновича
his son Samuil
его сына Самуила
Barsukov, in Shatsky,
Барсукова в Шатскому
go, I mean, to Shatsky, so if in
езди в смысле в Шатском так если в
Shatsky district it's not Russian, it's either a
шатском уезде это не русский это либо
Belarusian or Ukrainian
белорусский либо украинский
clan, Shatsky district - that's it,
род шатский уезд -
no, that's Tambov province, there are
это А нет это Тамбовская губерния там
Shatskys there, yes, that means it's not ours, so the Barsukovs, yes,
есть Шатские да это значит не наш так
perhaps, that's it, yes, Russian Russian, but
да возможно это да российский русский да
he doesn't have any Tatar
вот у него нету каких-то там татарских
roots, yes, the Barsukovs counted them, and the
корней да так Барсуковы засчитали и
Belkins, and the Belkins, and the
Белкины
Moscow
да и Белкины так московские
biers, for the sake of interest, I've never
биеры ради интереса я про таких не
heard of such people before, yes, yes, I haven't heard of them either,
слышал раньше да так да я тоже не слышал
all Belkins are out of the question, look, Belkins, the
всё белкины отпадает смотри Белкины
origin of the family history, honor the
происхождение истории рода почитай
ancestor of the family, a wonderful husband, Amanda Busala
предок рода дивный муж Аманда Бусала
Bussovala, honor, Margrave, left
Буссовала честью Марграф выехал из
Prussia  to the Grand Duke Danilo
Пруссии к великому князю Данилу
Alexandrovich all this is generally not Russian
Александровичу всё это вообще не русский
missed it means yes badger so far
пропустил значит да барсуковый пока пока
only Barsukov even Belkins are not Russian well okay let's
только Барсуков даже Белкины не русский
say they found a drop in the ocean
ну хорошо допустим нашли каплю в море да
and the question is the question
и вопрос вопрос
uh whose state was it this
ээ чьё это было государство вот это
Moscow Principality what kind of
Московское княжество како какого
ethnicity hmm what
этноса хм какого
ethnicity it
этноса
turns out Turkic some kind of ethnicity
получается тюркских каких-то о этносов
because if we look
потому что если мы смотрим
at Ukraine at that time yes it was in the
в Украине в эти времена да она была в
Principality of Lithuania Russian and
Княжестве Литовском русском и
Zhemanty then in this in the Polish-Lithuanian
Жемантийском потом в этой в Речи
Commonwealth yes we had here uh these
Посполитой да у нас тут были ээ эти
noble families well how not noble shlya
дворянские роды ну как не дворянские шля
szlachta is called that is Russian our
шляхта называется то есть русского наше
Ukrainian there Kostyantynno Troysky
украинского там Костянтинно Тройский
for example yes for example and others a bunch of they were of
наприклад да например и другие куча они
local origin that's exactly and
местного происхождения были вот именно а
in the Moscow Principality yes it turns out
в Московском княжестве да получается
then in the
потом в
kingdom of non-Slavic how is it
царстве не славянского как так
possible that uh the
получается возможно такое что ээ
Moscow Principality did not consist of
московское княжество состояло не из
Slavs what do you think of
славян как ты думаешь
course oh
конечно
interesting because we if we take
о интересно ведь мы если мы возьмём
when Moscow was founded and even  those there
когда основывали Москву и даже те там
thirteenth yes let's see when for
тринадцатые да вот давай посмотрим когда
example in modern Ukraine yes on the
например в Украине современной да на
territory of Rus' lived here Polyane Drevlyane
территории Руси жили тут поляне древляне
Ulich Tiver and other Slavic tribes
улич тивер и другие славянские племена
what Slavic tribes lived on the
какие славянские племена жили на
territory of Moscow
территории Москвы
oh history fifth grade none
ух история пятый класс
simply none means none not even the
никаких просто никаких значит никаких
fifth grade none simply A
даже не пятый класс никаких просто
question: what do you think Russians
А вопрос: ты как считаешь русские
Ukrainians one
украинцы один
people
народ
mm well somehow it's already clear I not that in
мм ну как-то уже понятно я не то что по
history somehow straight
истории как-то прям
Well what do you think my strong point well
Ну ты как считаешь моя сильная сторона
so culturally and genetically I think
ну так культурно и генетически я думаю
that no
что нет
different peoples right that's common
разные народы правильно вот это здравый
sense because when they tell us that
смысл потому что когда нам говорят что
we are one people and so
мы один народ и так
on
дальше
and interesting do you have any questions
а интересно у тебя есть какие-то вопросы
yes no in general no it was informative about
да нет в целом нет было познавательно по
you No you no then we can still just I
ты Нет ты нет то мы можем ещё просто я
think maybe you have you by
думаю может у тебя есть ты по
nationality who are you saying that there is a
национальности кто ты говоришь что есть
little eastern
чуть восточного
well it turns out yes on my
а ну это получается да со стороны
grandmother's side I have eastern
бабушки у меня восточная
and so my family in general how to
а так у меня семья в общем-то как
say from Ukraine they moved somewhere well a
сказать из Украины они переехали где-то
little more than 100 years ago it turns out
ну чуть больше 100 лет назад получается
somewhere and where did they move to Novosibirsk
где-то а куда переехали в Новосибирск
yeah because they were distributing land there and all that
ага потому что там землю раздавали и все
stuff that's why they moved and on my grandmother's side it's
дела вот поэтому переехали а по бабушке
eastern because eastern is a
восточноя это что потому что восточноя -
strong
это сильно
mm I honestly didn't give much detail but
мм я честно не очень дал подробности но
she has Tatar roots that's how I
у неё татарские корни вот так
understood and how do you think now Putin
понял а как сейчас считаешь вот Путин
said there that this is uh this is Russian land
там заявлял что это ээ это русская земля
Kyiv and so on that Ukraine doesn't
Киев и так дальше что Украины никакой не
exist the Ukrainian people don't
существует украинского народа не
exist and so on why did
существует и так дальше почему вот так
your government behave like this now
ваше государство сейчас повело себя
m in terms of this is the thesis of
м в плане вот это вот сам тезис
propaganda that the Ukrainian kingdom doesn't
пропаганды что украинское царство не
exist or that well yes this justifies the
существует или что ну да это оправдывает
war or is that really what all
войну или это действительно так все
people in Russia think
думают люди в России
we had such a long conversation
вот у нас такой длинный разговор был
of course it only justifies the war I
конечно это только оправдывает войну
understood but do people think so well yes
понял а думают ли так люди ну да
naturally quite a lot of people think so
естественно довольно многие так
I
думают я
used to communicate more like this somehow I
раньше больше скажем так общался как-то
kept statistics for myself how many
вёл для себя статистику сколько
percent there support and how many don't
процентов там поддерживает сколько нет
now I don't know probably for the last 6
вот сейчас не знаю наверное последние 6
months I can't
месяцев не
say exactly how many support and
скажу точно сколько там поддерживает
how many are against
сколько против
and do you have friends who died
а у тебя знакомые есть которые погибли
in the war
на войне
and no no
а нет нет
you hang out in other circles yeah well yeah I
ты в других кругах крутишься да
understood how do you
понял как ты
think Ukraine has something to do with
считаешь Украина имеет отношение к
Kievan Rus
Киевской Руси
[music]
[музыка]
Well, I think that yes, well, naturally,
ну думаю что да ну естественно
historically it has a bearing in terms of
историческое имеет отношение в плане
because many Russians say that
потому что многие россияне говорят что
on the contrary, Ukraine does not have it, but Russia does, well,
наоборот Украина не имеет а Россия имеет
after our long
ну Россия уже после нашего долгого
conversation, Russia has already debatably had a bearing, we
разговора уже спорно имеет отношение мы
already Yes, we already sorted it out by the way, if
уже Да мы уже так разобрали кстати если
I'm not mistaken, then on the,
я не ошибаюсь то на
uh, hat, if I'm not mistaken, of Alexander
ээ шапке если я не ошибаюсь Александра
Nevsky there was Arabic script, well, now so that
Невского была арабская вязь а ну сейчас
I don't get confused, I just love facts,
я чтобы я не спутал я просто люблю факты
so yes,
так
on the hat, here's Alexander
да на шапке вотми на на шлёме Александра
Nevsky's helmet, yes, Arabic script,
Невского да арабская вяз
look, there's a piece of text coming out of the tap, like, well,
посмотри там из крана кусочек текста
yes, it looks like, let's
ну да он выглядит как
say, well, like, in
такой скажем
short, like in cartoons, yes, no,
так ну такой короче как в мультиках
Arabic script, so there is
всяких там да арабски нет так та там
Arabic text on it, well,
именно текст арабский на нём есть а ну
yes, it doesn't have any form, yes, that is,
да это не не по форме имеет да то есть
look, write there, the helmet of Alexander
посмотри вот напиши там шлём Александра
Yanetsky, there is Arabic script, and there will be a bunch of
Янецкого там арабская вязь и будет куча
photographs, and so on, the
и фотографии и так дальше
question is: how is it like that,
вопрос: как
well, I'll throw in some food for thought,
вот так хорошо пищу для размышлений
think about it, read it, good
закину подумай над этим почитай давай
luck,
удачи
and if  someone doesnt believe something
да и если кто-то что-то не верит
Internet 21st century you can check everything
интернет XXI век вы можете всё проверить
if you have brains in a couple of
если у вас есть мозги за пару
minutes
минут
everything like this subscribe to my Telegram
всё вот так подпишись на мий Telegram
right now axis vin and
прямо зараз ось він а
popik its even more and more important youtube is
попик це дуже и дуже важливо youtube
banning us through kargeorki into a shadow
заганяе нас через каргеорки в тіньовий
ban and even more video is not shown to
бан и дуже багато відео не показуется
people information is often not shown
людям вчасно не показуется інформація
about streaming in order for us to have a short
про стрими тому для того щоб ми мали
operational connection, subscribe directly
оперативный зв'язок підпишиться прям
and there is a pop there in the telegram okmdeo, there
зараз а попик там в телеграмі окмдео ще
is also useful and useful information and we are
теж є цікава и корисна інформація и мы
responsible for you to trim the permanent
повинні з вами тримати постійний
operational connection regardless of that and
оперативный зв'язок незалежно від того
show you about it  YouTube glory to
чи покаже вам про цей YouTube слава
Ukraine subscribe
Украине підпишись